Sajad Hussain

React Native Developer

Experienced React Native developer with a passion for mobile app development. Experience on working and maintaining large and complex mobile apps. Creative mind and excited to learn new technologies. Delivered well-structured pixel perfect UI while maintaining reusability and scalability of code. Currently exploring TypeScript and Testing.

sajad1820375@gmail.com

Sringar, India

github.com/sajad786

+917006824513

in linkedin.com/in/sajad-hussain-09851320b

WORK EXPERIENCE

React Native Developer Code Brew Labs

12/2021 - Present Chandigarh Software development and mobile app development organization. Achievements/Tasks

- Developed cross platform apps according to client's requirement using React Native.
- Hands on experience with **Redux Toolkit**, **TypeScript**, **React** Hooks and JavaScript fundamentals.
- Worked with In app purchase, Geolocation, google maps, webView, Stripe and Paypal Sdk integration, native camera, calendar and Rest API.
- Good knowledge of **React Navigation**, Code splitting, Notification Service, Social login using firebase and Native
- Knowledge of uploading apps on Google Play Console and Apple Store Connect.
- Good Knowledge of debugging and working with animations using React Native Reanimated.
- Created multiple projects from scratch and modified existing codebases to accomodate new features.
- Used **Github** for version control.

Web Designer

Fortech Solutions

2020 - 2021

Softaware development, web development and app development Achievements/Tasks

- developed web sites using html, css is and bootstrap.
- Hands on experience with ,media query, bootstrap, Jquery, Css, html and JavaScript fundamentals.
- had an experience in **photoshop**, designed banners, posters

SKILLS



PROJECTS

TABADUL

- Created UI for swaping and buy products, uploading products and showing products of others.
- Added functionality to chat with vendors after swaping projects or
- Added firebase notification service for swap or buy request.
- Added filters on notifications based on pending, accepted and rejected. And added filter on products based on nearby, A-Z, newest

BiteTrucks

- implemented MapView and showed the trucks moving on map, based on vendor status if closed, onMove.
- implemented sockets to get the updated lat long of vendors based on the change of vendors lat longs.
- Bite trucks application designed for food and delivery.

- Pick and Drop flow ;- Designed for customers and drivers .
- implemented razorPay payment integration
- Deployed application on play store and app store connect.

RoyoOrders / RoyoDispatcher(Product)

- Multiple Vendor Modes: The royoOrders app supports various vendor modes, providing a versatile experience to customers: like Takeaway, Dine-in, Appointment, P2P, book and ride etc
- RoyoDispatcher has multiple functions like Order Assignment, Driver Acceptance, Navigation, Order Details, Real-time Tracking, Communication etc

EDUCATION

B.Tech(Computer Science)

Quest Group of Institutions, chandigarh

08/2018 - 07/2022 CGPA: 8.0

Senior Secondary

Govt. Boys Higher secondary school pattan 09/2017

ACHIEVEMENTS

Sainik School Compitative examination (06/2011)

Cracked competitive examination in sainik school for 6th class admission.

LANGUAGES

Enalish Full Professional Proficiency Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency